Sara Sultana

Administrative management/admission counsellor / sales/counselling/Recruitment

Hyderabad, Telangana 2saraacademics@gmail.com

+91 81067 11633

I am passionate, skilled and talented professional, currently shifted career in recruitment home based jobs, previously had experience in school administration, career counselling, teaching, curriculum planning, execution and implementation of educational programs at all levels.

Work Experience

Technology Associate/ UK IT Recruiter

Smart Edge Solutions - Hyderabad, Telangana January 2022 to May 2022

- Sourcing the profiles from various Job portals & networks and other internal data according to the client requirements.
- Creating and placing Job postings to attract candidates updating the postings, employee reference, data bank, etc..
- Screening, short listing, scheduling interviews.
- Organizing telephonic or personal interviews.
- Maintenance of individual records of personnel and documentation.
- Maintaining complete database of candidates
- Handling the requirements from all over UK and Europe.

Principal & teacher

Integral Foundation School - Hyderabad, Telangana March 2019 to January 2021

- Function as the head of the office and carry out all academic and administrative duties.
- Assisted in virtual cluster management and online instructional practice, design, implementaion and management.
- Solely responsible for profit and loss of the institution.
- · Headed English and science pre primary and primary curriculum development
- Involved in marketing, promotion and financial budget planning.
- · Headed recruitment drives.
- Conducted employee orientation, training and development, performance evaluation and management.
- Successfully taught high school english and biological science

Centre Manager

little Tuplis Pre school - Hyderabad, Telangana May 2018 to March 2019

- Supervisepreschool teachersandchildcare workers
- Hire and train new staff members
- Provide professional development opportunities for staff

- Establish policies and communicate them to staff and parents
- Develop educational programs and standards
- Maintain instructional excellence
- Assist staff in communicating with parents and children
- Meet with parents and staff to discuss students' progress
- Prepare budgets and allocate program funds
- Ensure that facilities are maintained and cleaned according to state regulation

Vice Principal/academic coordinator /teacher

Success the School - Hyderabad, Telangana March 2016 to April 2018

- Headed academic and administrative duties.
- Leading , designing activities to ensure maximum admissions of quality students.
- Established continued relations with stakeholders for brand building.
- · Headed science primary school curriculum development, implementation and management.

Biological science teacher & coordinator

Azra public school - Hyderabad, Telangana June 2014 to April 2016

Successfully taught 2 years as a high school biological science and English teacher , creating interest and curiosity for the subject in children

Science Teacher

Princess Esin Girls high school - Hyderabad, Telangana June 2013 to April 2014

Education

Bachelor's in Bachelors of education

Presidency college for education April 2012 to June 2013

Master's in Hr

Osmania University - Hyderabad, Telangana 2008 to 2010

B.Sc

St.Ann's College 2008

Skills / IT Skills

- Computer skills
- Organizational skills
- Recruiting
- HR sourcing
- Payroll

- Human resources
- Talent acquisition
- Training & development

Certifications and Licenses

Early Childhood Care And Development from Akhsara institute 2016January 2016 to June 2016

Phonetic from Jolly Phonics UK Webinar in 2021

Applying Strategic Leadership in Education in 2018